Syed Ali Raza

085 209 9600 | Apt 2, 3 Dublin Road, Portlaoise | Permission: EU Stamp 4

isyedaliraza@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/isyedaliraza | github.com/isyedaliraza

Summary

I'm a Software Engineer with over 5 years of experience in Full-stack development. I have worked with a variety of technologies like Flutter, React, Node.js, Django, Odoo, WordPress, Unity etc. I am a quick learner and love to learn new things. I always look for ways to improve my skills and build better software.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Senior Software Engineer

2020 - 2024

Business and Digital Technology Center – Baramej®

Muscat, OM

- Implemented 3D data center infrastructure management system. Integrated IoT devices and third-party systems like PBX for SMS and Phone alerts.
- Developed a middleware insurance platform in Python and JavaScript, linking Omantel and Ooredoo with third-party insurance brokers.
- Developed metaverse identity for Ministry of Transport Communications and Information Technology using Unity.
- Developed and published a number of applications with features such as OAuth, payment integration, google maps integration, order management, booking management etc.
- Designed and developed REST APIs using Django, Flask, Node.js, Firebase Cloud Functions, and Laravel.
- Conducted training and knowledge transfer sessions.
- Managed administration related tasks such as processing sales and purchase invoices, communicating with customers via phone & email, filing & scanning paperwork etc.

Full Stack Developer

2018 - 2020

Tilal Al Sad Projects and Investment L.L.C

Muscat, OM

- Developed and maintained responsive websites using Wordpress and Drupal.
- Designed and developed intuitive UIs using React, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, and Figma enhancing user experience.
- Modernized legacy systems by porting vanilla PHP projects to Node.js, improving performance and maintainability.

EDUCATION

National University of Computer and Emerging Sciences	Islamabad, PK
Bachelor of Science - Computer Science	2013 - 2017
FG Degree College for Men Intermediate – Pre-Engineering	Wah Cantt, PK 2011 – 2013
POF Model High School	Wah Cantt, PK
Matriculation	2011 - 2013

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, JavaScript, Dart, Swift, Java, C++, HTML/CSS, SQL, NoSQL, JSON, XML Frameworks: Flutter, React, Next.js, Odoo, Node.js, Django, Laravel, WordPress, Drupal, Bootstrap,

Tailwind CSS

Developer Tools: Git, GitHub, Jira, Slack, Docker, Google Cloud Platform, Neovim, VS Code, PyCharm,

IntelliJ, Xcode, Android Studio

Design Tools: Figma, Adobe XD, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Photopea

Interpersonal Skills

Learning, Problem-solving, Teamwork/ Collaboration, Self-motivation, Ability to work under pressure, Time management, Adaptability, Responsibility, Communication

ACHIEVEMENTS

Was awarded fully-funded ICT scholarship (Prime Minister's National ICT Scholarship Award) to pursue Bachelor's degree in Computer Science

PUBLICATIONS

S. Nizami, A. Basharat, A. Shaukat, U. Hameed, S. A. Raza, A. Bekele, R. Giffen, and J. R. Green, "CEA: Clinical Event Annotator mHealth Application for Real-time Patient Monitoring," in the Proc. of 40th Annual International Conference of the IEEE Engineering in Medicine and Biology Society (EMBC'18), Honolulu, HI, USA, July 17-21, 2018.

Hobbies & Interests

Learning new things, Cybersecurity, Machine Learning, Gaming, Travelling, Food

References

Available upon request